Guide to the Blake and Rood families papers, 1847-1906
Blake and Rood families papers, 1847-1906
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Blake and Rood families papers, 1847-1906, 1847-1891 (bulk).
3485
.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes letters (1847-1868) from Helen Rood to her brother Ogden Nicholas Rood and his wife Mathilde concerning family and friends in New Haven, Connecticut; religion; female education; Eli Whitney Blake, whom she married in 1860; her impressions of Heidelberg, where her husband studied; and German and English sentiment concerning the American Civil War. Letters (1859-1891) from Eli Blake to Ogden Rood concerning scientific experiments; his work as professor at Cornell University; and his work at Brown University as professor of physics. Other correspondence includes letters to Eli Blake concerning the National Bell Telephone Company, the University of Virginia, and Troy University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Eli Whitney Blake was the first professor of physics at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes letters (1847-1868) from Helen Rood to her brother Ogden Nicholas Rood and his wife Mathilde concerning family and friends in New Haven, Connecticut; religion; female education; Eli Whitney Blake, whom she married in 1860; her impressions of Heidelberg, where her husband studied; and German and English sentiment concerning the American Civil War. Letters (1859-1891) from Eli Blake to Ogden Rood concerning scientific experiments; his work as professor at Cornell University; and his work at Brown University as professor of physics. Other correspondence includes letters to Eli Blake concerning the National Bell Telephone Company, the University of Virginia, and Troy University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Blake family.; Blake, Eli Whitney, 1836-1895.; Blake, Helen Rood, 1832-1869.; Rood, Ogden Nicholas, 1831-1902.; Rudd family.
Subjects:
Physics--1859-1891.; Physicists.; College teachers.
Places:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Foreign public opinion--English--German.; Heidelberg (Germany)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Eli Whitney Blake, 1859-1870 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Eli Whitney Blake, 1871-1875 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Eli Whitney Blake, 1876-1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Helen Rood Blake, 1847-1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Helen Rood Blake, 1856-1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Helen Rood Blake, 1859-1861 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Helen Rood Blake, 1862-1868 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Margaret Rood, 1850-1857 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ogden Nicholas Rood, 1853-1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Others (Francis Blake, Blankman, Franek Bright, George J. Brush, Barclay Hazard, E. Hungerford, MacWhorter, M.G. Ogden, Roland S. Rood), 1853-1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Others re: New England Telephone and National Bell Telephone Company (Thomas E. Bailey, George L. Bradley, William R. Driver, C.E. Hubbard, George A. Miner, H.C. Wainright & Co.), 1878-1881 (Box 1, Folder 11)